(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
みんな、おんゆ〜
Everyone, on-yu~!
今日は姫森ルーナ3周年記念ということで
Today is Himemori Luna's 3rd anniversary,
あるホロメンたちとずっとやりたいなと思っていたことをするのらよ
and I'm going to do something I've wanted to do
with some Holo-members for a long time!
まずはハッシュタグはこちらの「#姫森ルーナ3周年記念」でツイートしてのらね
First off, please tweet using the hashtag
'#HimemoriLuna3rdAnniversary'!
ということでそろそろホロメンが来るから準備するのら
The Holo-members should be arriving soon,
so I'll get ready.
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ...
Heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho...
遊びに来たぞ〜
We're here to play!
来た来た来た〜
We're here, we're here!
いやいや、いかつ！待っていかつすぎ！
Whoa, whoa, intense! Wait, that's way too intense!
え、何、準備万端じゃん
Wait, what? You're totally ready!
やば、何それ、ルーナさん
Whoa, what is that, Luna-san?
みんなにドヤっとるじゃないですか
You're showing off to everyone!
よく来たのらに〜
Welcome, everyone!
あ、3周年おめでとう！
Oh, happy 3rd anniversary!
おめでとう〜！
Congratulations!
だからそれなんやねん！
So, what is that thing?!
今日はね、チョコルーナたんでVRホラゲーをやるのらぞ！
Today, the three of us are going to
play a VR horror game!
ブイアールホラゲー！？
VR horror game!?
え、おい大丈夫なのかお前、VRホラゲーといえば過去を思い出せ
Hey, are you going to be okay?
Remember what happened in the past with VR horror games.
そんなこともありましたけど、今日は万全の体制でやらせてもらうので大丈夫なのらよ
That did happen, but I'm fully prepared today,
so I'll be fine!
なるほどね、安心してくださいということですね
I see, so you're telling us not to worry.
安心して、みんな大丈夫だから
Don't worry, everyone will be fine.
でも、ちょっとボタンちゃんいないのらよね
But Botan-chan isn't here.
あ、ボタンちゃんですか？
Ah, Botan-chan?
そうなんです、ボタンちゃんは残念だけど来られなくて
That's right, unfortunately Botan-chan couldn't make it.
ボタンちゃ〜ん！
Botan-chaaan!
でもメッセージはもらってきたからスバルが代読します
But she sent a message, so I'll read it for her.
本当？お願いします
Really? Please do.
お手紙をちょっと聞きたいから一旦外すのら
I want to hear the letter, so I'll take this off for a second.
偉い、外せて偉い
Good girl, taking it off properly.
「んなたん、3周年おめでとう！」
“Nna-tan, happy 3rd anniversary!”
ありがちゅ、ボタンちゃん
Thank you, Botan-chan.
「今日、急用で一緒に遊べなくて無念...」
“I'm so sorry I couldn't join you today
due to some urgent business...”
悲しい...
So sad...
「なので、4周年の時はみんなでVRエアホッケーで勝負しよう！(ボーリングでも可)」
“So, for your 4th anniversary, let's all play
VR air hockey! (Or bowling works too).”
「これからも末長くよろしくー！」だそうです
“I look forward to being friends for a long time!”
That's what she said.
ボタンちゃん！マジVRエアホッケーいいの？大丈夫？また泣かせちゃうけど大丈夫かな？
Botan-chan! Are you sure about VR air hockey?
Is it okay? I might make you cry again, is that okay?
泣かせちゃうって、何があったの？
Make her cry? What happened?
ボタンちゃん、エアホッケーだとね、普段聞いたことないような叫びを上げるのらよ
When Botan-chan plays air hockey, she lets out
screams you've never heard before.
そうなの！？
Really!?
牡丹逆転劇始まるけど。楽しみなのらに〜
The Botan comeback drama begins.
I'm looking forward to it!
それはまた今度やるということで。今日はね、3人でファズモフォビアをプレイしようと思うのら
Well, we'll do that another time. Today,
the three of us are going to play Phasmophobia!
あの伝説の！やばい、怖そう！
That legendary game! Oh no, it looks scary!
と思うけど、みんな早くこれをつけるのら。後ろ向いて！
So, everyone, put these on quickly. Turn around!
わかった！オッケー！
Got it! Okay!
よいしょ、よいしょ...
Heave-ho, heave-ho...
よいしょ、よいしょ、よいしょ...
Heave-ho, heave-ho, heave-ho...
ほーい。
Hoi.
行くぜー！
Let's go!
準備できたんならね...
Since we're all ready...
行くぞ！
Let's do this!
おー！
Ohh!
これで行くぞー！
We're going in with this!
それじゃ、いざ、ファズモフォビア！
Well then, let's head into Phasmophobia!
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
よーし、みんな準備できたんなら...
Alright, if everyone is ready...
レッツ・ゴータ！
Let's go-ta!
じゃあ、早速、ファズモフォビアやっていくのら！
Then, let's start playing Phasmophobia right away!
始まる、始まる！
It's starting, it's starting!
レッチョジョンで、みんな、そこスタンバイの...
Okay, everyone, stand by over there and...
コルクボード選んで。
Select the corkboard.
おっけー。
Okay.
コルクボード選んだ？ スタンバイ、押し... 押します。
Did you pick the board? I'll... I'll press standby.
ルーナが押せてない！
Luna hasn't pressed it!
ルーナ様、押して。
Luna-sama, press it.
人差し指や！
Use your index finger!
すみません、中指やってました。
Sorry, I was using my middle finger.
まずは、操作確認のため一勝負。
First, we'll do one match to check the controls.
その様子を、ダイジェストでお届けするのら！
I'll show you how that went in this digest!
それじゃ、まず、アイテムを持ちましょう。
Well then, first, let's grab some items.
はい。え、何？この青いやつ。
Okay. Eh, what's this? This blue thing.
どれ？ あ、それ温度計。
Which one? Ah, that's the thermometer.
チョコ先生、温度計ね。
Choco-sensei, you take the thermometer.
おっけー。
Okay.
じゃあ、ルーナ、これ机の上に置いてきて。
Then Luna, go place this on a table.
机の上に本？ 本？
A book on the table? A book?
さあ、これを置いてくれ。
Come on, place this.
さあ、スバルはカメラ持って。
And Subaru will take the camera.
よし、行くぞ！
Alright, let's go!
雨降ってる。
It's raining.
傘ある？
Do we have umbrellas?
ないのら。
We don't.
やべー、お漏らし気味。
Damn, it's like I'm leaking.
スバルがまずは鍵を開けるぜ！
Subaru's gonna unlock the door first!
開けて、開けて。
Open it, open it.
ほら！
There!
お邪魔しまーす！
Coming in!
お邪魔するぜ！
Pardon the intrusion!
ここに本置いて。
Place the book here.
ここに本...
Put the book here...
あ、落っこっちゃった。
Ah, it fell.
落っこっちゃうよ。
It keeps falling.
あ、じゃあ、こっちでもいいよ。あ、待て。場所を...
Ah, then this way is fine too. Ah, wait. The spot...
ルーナ、立っちゃうよ。
Luna, it's standing up.
この子、何で頑張ってんの？
Why is this thing trying so hard?
ルーナ、こっちだ。EMF持ってこーい。
Luna, over here. Bring the EMF.
あ、こっち来て。
Ah, come here.
はい。
Okay.
青いよ、青いよ。
It's blue, it's blue.
はい。明るくしたから大丈夫ですよ。
Yes. I've turned the lights on, so it's okay.
チョコ先生、どう？
Choco-sensei, how is it?
あ、待て、チョコ先生、勇気がすごい！
Ah, wait, Choco-sensei, you're so brave!
地下を攻めてる！
She's attacking the basement!
ひえー！
Hieee!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
地下はあかん！
The basement is bad news!
ルーナも行くのらー！
Luna's going too!
落ち着いて、落ち着いて行くぞ。
Calm down, let's take it slow.
なんかね、指紋はね、こういうドアとかの、ここに出たりとかする。
You know, fingerprints show up on things like these doors.
チョコ先生、指紋だ。
Choco-sensei, fingerprints.
なんか、ついてる？
Is something there?
そう、なんか出たりはする。あと、こっちだ、こっちの部屋見てない。
Yeah, something shows up. Also, this way, we haven't seen this room.
ドアのあ... あった！指紋！
On the door... There it is! Fingerprints!
嘘！
No way!
指紋出てる、出てる！
Fingerprints are showing up!
指紋にチェックだ。
Check the fingerprints.
指紋... 指紋チェックオッケー。
Fingerprints... fingerprint check okay.
お、ここ、この辺ね、よく出る。
Oh, right around here, they show up often.
青いです、青いです。
It's blue, it's blue.
お、電気が消えた。
Oh, the lights went out.
いたずらや！
It's a prank!
真っ暗になってる！
It's pitch black!
あ、チョコ先生、どこだ？
Ah, Choco-sensei, where are you?
チョコ先生、お前どこにいんだよ！
Choco-sensei, where the heck are you!
みんな、いない！
Everyone's gone!
おった、おった！ いた、いた！
There you are! Found you!
こっちが玄関、帰るぞ。
The entrance is this way, let's head back.
指紋とあと何があったんだっけ？
We had fingerprints and what else?
指紋しかないのら。まだ指紋だけ。
Only fingerprints. Just fingerprints so far.
じゃあ、次これやりに行こう。
Then let's go try this next.
「アピールしてください」作戦や。
It's the "Please give us a sign" operation.
お、出た、出た！
Oh, it's out, it's out!
アピールして。
Give us a sign.
誰かいますかー？
Is anyone there?
いた？ ついた？
Was there someone? Did it turn on?
ついてない。これ雷だ。
It didn't. That was thunder.
あ、今ここ3.9。
Ah, it's 3.9 here right now.
2.3。
2.3.
下がってる。
It's dropping.
でも氷点下じゃない？
But isn't it freezing?
1.5。
1.5.
うわ、どんどん下がってるね。
Whoa, it's dropping fast.
起きた、起きた、起きた！
It happened, it happened, it happened!
オレンジになった。オレンジ。
It turned orange. Orange.
ルーナオレンジになった。
Luna, it turned orange.
キッチン？
Kitchen?
キッチンに何？
What's in the kitchen?
今の声？
Was that a voice?
なんかハァみたいなやつ。
Something like 'ha...'
氷点下かな。
Is it freezing temperature?
氷点下あった？
Was there freezing temperature?
え、あったよね、ちょこ先生。
Wait, we had it, right, Choco-sensei?
あった。
We did.
指紋と氷点下にチェックが付くのな。
So fingerprints and freezing temperatures are checked.
オーケー。
Okay.
なんだルーナ意外と大丈夫じゃん。
What, Luna is doing fine actually.
写真撮ろうぜ。
Let's take a photo.
はい、みんな、せい、の...
Alright everyone, ready, set...
チーズ！
Cheese!
撮れたの？
Did you get it?
ルーナどこいんの？
Luna, where are you?
ルーナキッチンじゃなくてソファのとこにいたのいよ。
Luna wasn't in the kitchen, she was by the sofa.
オーケー、そこでも。
Okay, there too.
どこ？今キッチンに来てるよ。
Where? I'm in the kitchen now.
せーの、え、撮ってるね。
Ready, set... Oh, taking it.
はい、ハイチーズ。
Alright, say cheese.
うわーい！
Yay!
なんかビープ音鳴ってる。
Something is beeping.
オレンジ！絶対来たい、絶対来たい！
Orange! It's definitely coming, it's definitely coming!
ひえあああ！
Hieeee!
おい、誰だよ今ドア閉めたやつ。
Hey, who closed the door just now?
誰かいるようなドア閉めたやつ。
Whoever closed that door...
あれ、ルーナどこいる？
Wait, where is Luna?
え、死んだ？
Wait, she died?
え？ルーナ死んでる！
What? Luna is dead!
死んでるー！
She's dead!
ルーナちゃん殺されちゃったー！
Luna-chan was killed!
指紋があって氷点下があって...
There were fingerprints and freezing temperature...
スピリットボックスなんかハァーみたいのがあった。
On the Spirit Box, there was something like 'ha...'
ハァあった。
There was a 'ha'.
ハァあったら、ちょっと待って。
If there was a 'ha', wait a second.
えーと、ゴーストオーブ、あ、待って、オーブはどう？
Um, Ghost Orb... wait, what about the orb?
オーブ？
Orb?
あと写真とか見よう。
Let's check the photos too.
誰か写真撮ってた。
Someone took a photo.
カメラねえ！
There's no camera!
どっか置いてきたわ、あぶねー、カメラさっき揉みくちゃで落とした。
I left it somewhere, dangerous, I dropped the camera in the scuffle earlier.
やばいでも、今行ったら確実に死ぬ。ちょっと待って。
This is bad, if I go now I'll definitely die. Wait a second.
ミミックじゃない？
Isn't it a Mimic?
ミミックじゃね？
It's a Mimic, right?
これはミミックですね。
This is a Mimic.
じゃあミミックにしてみっか。
Then let's go with Mimic.
丸つけた。
I circled it.
当たってますように。
I hope it's right.
じゃあルーナ、またな。またねー。
Then Luna, see ya. Bye bye!
助けてー。
Help me...
頑張れよ、しゅばー、ルーナちゃんまたねー。
Good luck, Suba. Luna-chan, see ya later!
あー、ジン。ジン！ジンだった。
Ah, Jin. Jin! It was a Jin.
ジンだって、あらー。
It was a Jin, oh dear.
本当だ、ブレーカーをオフにすると、移動速度を制限することができる。
True, turning off the breaker limits its movement speed.
終わっちまったよ。
It's over.
終わっちまった、これはどうだ、もう一回なのか？
It's over, how about this, one more time?
もう一回やろう！
Let's do it one more time!
いいよ、いいよ、やろう。
Sure, sure, let's do it.
ルーナ余裕そうだしな。
Luna seems to have room to spare.
いける、なんかいける気がしてきた。
I can do it, I feel like I can do it now.
本当？
Really?
いきます。
Here we go.
フォトカメラ、UVライト、スピリットボックス、懐中電灯、あとあれがない。
Photo camera, UV light, Spirit box, flashlight, and that's missing.
塩？あ、でも一つあるから。
Salt? Oh, we have one though.
え、塩で足跡やってみる？
Wait, should we try tracking footprints with salt?
え、いいよ。足跡？どうやって買うんだろ。
Oh, okay. Footprints? How do we buy it?
ストアで買って、これだ、塩あった。
Buy it at the store... here it is, found the salt.
購入、購入。買った。
Purchase, purchase. Bought it.
いい感じ。
Looking good.
大丈夫。
It's okay.
塩って追加されてる。オーケー。あったね。
Salt has been added. Okay. We have it.
いいね。いけるぜ、なな。
Nice. We can do this, Nana.
温度計も大丈夫だよね。
The thermometer is fine too, right?
温度計どれだ？一個買っとこう。
Which one is the thermometer? Let's buy one.
温度計入ってない？温度計って書いてないのな。
Isn't the thermometer included? It doesn't say thermometer.
温度...あ、リストにないのか。なるほどね。
Temper... oh, it's not on the list. I see.
これじゃない？購入。行ったらあるかも。
Isn't it this? Purchase. Maybe it'll be there when we go.
え、買っちゃった？買った？買っちゃった。
Wait, did you buy it? Did you buy it? You bought it.
買っちゃった。
Bought it.
オーケー。行こう行こう！ゴーゴーゴー！
Okay. Let's go, let's go! Go, go, go!
準備を整え、本戦に挑むスバチョコルーナ。
Subaru, Choco, and Luna prepare and head into the main battle.
ここからはノーカットでお届けするのら。
We'll bring you the rest unedited.
来た！かわいい！
It's here! So cute!
かわいすぎだろ！
You're too cute!
めっちゃしおる！
You're moving so much!
皆さん、それぞれ持ってください。
Everyone, please take something each.
さっきと同じ感じ？
The same as before?
一旦ね、覚えたやつ持てばね。
For now, just take what you remember.
これでいいかな？
Is this okay?
これと…これ。
This and... this.
これマジで何なんだろうね。
I wonder what this really is.
持ちました！
I've got them!
さっきと同じの持ったのら。
I took the same ones as before.
Okay、じゃスバルもこれ持つか。
Okay, then Subaru will take this too.
あ、いや、温度計持とう。
Ah, no, I'll take the thermometer.
じゃ温度計持ったよ。
Then I've got the thermometer.
はい！
Okay!
行くぞ！出発！Let's go!
Let's go! Departure! Let's go!
行くよ！
Let's go!
行くぞ！あ、なぜ投げた？
Let's go! Ah, why did you throw it?
すみません、テンション上がっちゃって。
Sorry, I just got over-excited.
Go go go go!
まあ最初わね、幽霊出ないんで。
Well, at first, ghosts won't appear.
わあ！怖くないのだよ！
Wah! I'm not scared!
なんだ怖くないのかよ！
What, so you're not scared?
怖くないのだ！
I'm not scared!
怖くないのだ！もう行けるのだ！
I'm not scared! I can go now!
追いかけまわしてくる奴いるらしいぞ。
I heard there's one that chases you around.
え？追いかけまわして？
Eh? Chasing around?
え、怖い…さっき追いかけてこなかった？
Eh, scary... Didn't it chase us before?
あ、確かに。
Ah, true.
ほら、確かに。
See, true.
怖い！
Scary!
Okay、電気点けまくり。
Okay, turning on all the lights.
EMFどこ？地下の電気どこにある？
Where's the EMF? Where's the basement light?
地下入って右。
Inside the basement, to the right.
お待たせ。
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Open!
電気…
The lights...
EMF反応なし。
No EMF response.
どこの電気…あ！
Where's the light... ah!
嘘！ついた！ありがとうって言ってくれて。
No way! It's on! Thanks for saying that.
スバルが点けたんだよ！
Subaru turned it on!
メンタル強すぎるやろ、どうなっとんねん。
Your mental strength is too high, what's with that?
え？だって…じゃルーナ本設置しまちょ。
Eh? But... well then Luna will set up the book.
はい、サイン書いてくれるかな？
Yes, I wonder if it will write a sign?
あれ、指紋ライト落としてどっかやっちゃった。
Oh, I dropped the fingerprint light somewhere.
なんでやんね！
What the heck!
何が？
What?
あった。
Found it.
何ね？指紋落とした？
What is it? You dropped the light?
しっちゃう！
I'll do it!
何やってんのよ。
What are you doing?
スバルーナやばい。
Subaruna is crazy.
うん？
Hm?
あ、でもまだ全然大丈夫ですね。
Ah, but it's still totally fine.
まだ全然平気なのね。
Still totally okay.
また本落としてる奴いるじゃん、大丈夫？
Someone dropped the book again, you okay?
なんで本落として…ルーナじゃないの…きゃ！
Why dropping the book... it wasn't Luna... Kya!
お、電気消えた？始まるぞ！
Oh, the lights went out? It's starting!
消えましたね！
They went out!
このタイミングであれ持って来るわ、「アピールしてください」奴。
At this timing, I'll bring that "Please appeal" one.
行くぞ！
Let's go!
きゃ！
Kya!
きゃー！
Kyaa!
I'm behind you...
え、今の何ね？
Eh, what was that?
スバルの声やよ！
That was Subaru's voice!
声お化けかと思った！
I thought it was a ghost voice!
え？今の声スバル？
Eh? That voice just now was Subaru?
嘘！
No way!
ちょっと、EMFめっちゃ反応してるんだけど、まだ。
Wait, the EMF is reacting a lot, still.
あ、スバルの声が怖い…怖くてよぉ…
Ah, Subaru's voice is scary... I'm so scared...
アピールしてください！
Please appeal!
アピールしてください！わあ！
Please appeal! Wah!
やめて！
Stop it!
アピールしてください！
Please appeal!
Where? アピールして！頼むまっそ！Go go go go!
Where? Appeal! I'm begging you! Go go go go!
Let's appeal time!
How are you? I'm fine thank you.
And you?
指紋とか無さそうやね。
Doesn't look like there are any fingerprints.
What's your name?
My name is Suba!
Nice to... まだ何も反応ねぇのだ。
Nice to... Still no response at all.
みんなで写真撮ろうぜ！
Let's take a photo together!
あ、写真撮る！
Ah, taking a photo!
どこ？リビング集合！
Where? Gather in the living room!
Okay、リビング。
Okay, the living room.
Cheese! Picture! Picture!
Say cheese! Okay!
ゴーストライティングだ！
Ghost writing!
まあね、キッチンのほうのテーブルに置いたのら。
Well, I put it on the kitchen table.
How are you?
I'm fine, thank you.
No sign.
No sign... ええ？
No sign... Eh?
お、ソロだ。
Oh, it's a solo (hunt).
触らないで。特に何も...
Don't touch it. There's nothing in particular...
No sign... 何も出てこないなあ。音も鳴らねえし。
No sign... Nothing's appearing. No sounds either.
あ、黄色くなった。
Ah, it turned yellow.
黄色い？
Yellow?
うん。カメラ見てくるか。
Yeah. Shall I go check the camera?
黄色です。今キッチンで黄色くなったのら。
It's yellow. It just turned yellow in the kitchen.
黄色。ちょっと喋るか。
Yellow. Let's talk a bit.
Hi! My name is Subaru. Chuba-! Chuba-!
How are you?
Chuba! Chuba chuba!
真っ暗。見えない。
Pitch black. I can't see.
I'm fine, thank you. And you?
Chuba! Chuba!
How are you?
Who-! A-! You-!
Who are you?
あ、真っ暗で見えない。真っ暗になっちゃった。ライト落としちゃった。
Ah, it's pitch black, I can't see. It's become pitch black. I dropped the light.
ライト落とした？
You dropped the light?
何も出てこないなあ。
Nothing's appearing.
な、もう、恐怖があります。
Jeez, I'm scared.
何も出ないな。
Nothing's appearing.
ねえ、真っ暗で何も見えない。みんな、どこ？
Hey, it's pitch black and I can't see anything. Everyone, where are you?
How are you?
え、どこ？みんな、どこ？
Eh, where? Everyone, where are you?
あった！おはよー！全然反応してない。
Found it! Good morning! It's not reacting at all.
怖い。怖い。カメラ設置できてない。
Scary. Scary. The camera isn't set up.
ん？カメラ？カメラ？
Hmm? Camera? Camera?
何もない。
There's nothing.
ないのら。どうしよ。どこにいるの？
There's nothing. What should we do? Where is it?
チョコせんぱーい、どこにいんだ？
Choco-senpai, where are you?
あ、ライトないから持っていけないのらよね。
Ah, I can't take it because I don't have a light.
チョコ！
Choco!
あ、いた。
Ah, there she is.
いた？
Found her?
いた。
Found her.
特に気温とかもないもんね、これ。
There isn't even any temperature change or anything.
何も反応... え、マジで、何にも活動してないぞ。
No reaction... Eh, seriously, there's no activity at all.
気温見るか。
Let's check the temperature.
大丈夫か、スバル。
Are you okay, Subaru?
しゃがんでるやん。
She's crouching.
おばけいらないのら。
I don't want a ghost.
Hey, who are you?
I'm fine, fine, fine.
ルーナたん、大丈夫？
Luna-tan, are you okay?
ちょっとキョロキョロして聴いてたのら。
I was looking around and listening.
塩置いた？
Did you place the salt?
いいね。何にも出てこん。後半に畳み掛けてくるタイプやな。
Nice. Nothing's appearing. It's the type that attacks in the latter half.
みんな、そういうのも入れた？
Everyone, did you put those in too?
わからん。
I don't know.
塩、とりあえず振りまいてる。
Anyway, I'm scattering salt.
悪霊退散！悪霊退散！
Evil spirits, begone! Evil spirits, begone!
塩ってどう反応するんだ？
How does salt react?
やばい！Questのバッテリーがないって言われてもーてます。
Oh no! It's telling me the Quest battery is low.
やばい、暗くなった。
Oh no, it got dark.
でも、塩も踏まれてないもんね。
But the salt hasn't been stepped on either.
なんだこいつ。意外と... スバルたちが大声で喚き散らかすからさ、ビビってんのかもな。
What's up with this? Unexpectedly... maybe it's scared because Subaru and the others are shouting so much.
どこや？指紋もないしな。
Where is it? No fingerprints either.
音も鳴らないな。え、じゃあ何なんだ、こいつ。
No sounds either. Eh, then what is this thing?
あと何ができる？
What else can we do?
え？
Eh?
お、車が！近くにいるということではないんですか？
Oh, the car! Doesn't that mean it's nearby?
どこ？
Where?
待って、声聞こえる。
Wait, I hear a voice.
声が！
A voice!
声聞こえる。
I hear a voice.
ここだ！うわー、声聞こえる！
It's here! Whoa, I hear a voice!
スバ！うわあああ！
Suba! Uwaaaa!
何？やばい、処刑タイムきてる。
What? Oh no, a hunt is starting.
これ？
This?
あああ、助けてー！うわああああ！
Aaaah, help! Uwaaaaa!
スバ！
Suba!
待って、どこ？あ、殺されちまったって。
Wait, where? Ah, she's been killed.
スバー！
Suba!
やばい！やばい！あ、どうすればいいの？出ればいい？
Oh no! Oh no! Ah, what should I do? Should I go out?
出ればいい？
Should I go out?
出ればいい！
Just go out!
やば！開けられない！開けて！ねえ、開けて！
Oh no! I can't open it! Open it! Hey, open it!
死守せよ！開けられた！
Defend to the death! It's open!
あれ？おい、敗走退散だ、みんな。あの、ドア壊れてるんだけど。
Huh? Hey, it's a rout, everyone. Um, the door is broken.
あきれました
I'm exasperated.
お待たせしました
Sorry to keep you waiting.
あれ？しゅばあ死んだ？
Huh? Did Shuba die?
しゅばあ
Shuba...
しゅばあ、あのドア壊れてるんですけど
Shuba, that door is broken...
壊れちゃった。
It broke.
ドアぶっ壊れてるんやないか！
Isn't the door completely wrecked?!
やだー、しゅばー、しゅばー
Nooo, Shuba, Shuba!
いったん戻ろう。戻ろう。
Let's go back for now. Let's go back.
声が聞こえた
I heard a voice.
ルナ頑張れ。
Good luck, Luna.
しゅばの仇を取ってくれ。
Avenge Shuba.
ってことは証拠が...
That means the evidence is...
なんだ？声聞こえて...
What is it? Hearing a voice...
スピリットボックスってこと？
Does that mean Spirit Box?
スピリットボックス。スピリットボックス。
Spirit Box. Spirit Box.
みんなここ見て、ここ見て。
Everyone look here, look here.
どこ？
Where?
看板見て、看板。
Look at the board, the board.
看板？
The board?
この写真見て。写真の、
Look at this photo. In the photo,
ここのチェックマーク。
this checkmark here.
チェックマーク？
Checkmark?
どれ？左下？
Which one? Bottom left?
そう
Yes.
あー！
Ah!
なんかこれ、えっ？
Wait, what's this? Eh?
これお化けなのか？
Is this a ghost?
えっ？どれ？
Eh? Which one?
コルクボードの左下。
Bottom left of the corkboard.
左下？
Bottom left?
この白いの？おー、かな。
This white thing? Oh, maybe.
ここが、EMFリーダーで
Wasn't it here that we found
超常現象の痕跡を発見したんじゃないすか。
traces of paranormal activity with the EMF reader?
チェックマークついてる。
There's a checkmark.
ってことは、このEMFレベル5ってこと？
So that means it's EMF Level 5?
5になったってことやね。
It means it hit Level 5.
これと、スピリットボックスチェックじゃないか？
This and Spirit Box check, right?
チェックやね。
Check indeed.
あと
Also,
ゴーストによる超常現象を目撃
witnessed a ghost event.
これは、うーん、氷点下、指紋...
This is, hmm, freezing temps, fingerprints...
温度、違う、
Temp, no,
ゴーストオーブ、プロジェクター？
Ghost Orbs, Projector?
あ、プロジェクターやってないわ。
Ah, we haven't done the projector yet.
えー、なんだ？なんだ？どれだ？
Eh, what is it? What is it? Which one?
ってことは、スピリットか
Does that mean it's a Spirit,
レイスかツインズってこと？じゃないかこれ。
Wraith, or Twins? Isn't that it?
そうだね。
Right.
えっ、どれだ？
Eh, which one is it?
あぶり出し。
Narrowing it down.
え、待って。じゃあ他の... おお。
Eh, wait. Then other... oh.
ゴーストライティングがあったらスピリット。
If there's Ghost Writing, it's a Spirit.
ゴーストライティングなかった。
There was no Ghost Writing.
ってことは、スピリットじゃなくて、あと何だっけ？
So it's not a Spirit, what else was there?
レイスかツインズ。
Wraith or Twins.
レイス、レイス、ツインズ。
Wraith, Wraith, Twins.
レイスとツインズ。
Wraith and Twins.
レイスがあとプロジェクターがあったらレイスで、
If it's a Wraith it would have Projector,
プロジェクターやってないね。
but we haven't done that.
で、ツインズが氷点下の温度やね。
And Twins is Freezing Temperatures.
氷点下にはなってない？
It hasn't reached freezing?
あ、でも温度...
Ah, but the temp...
ウナたん、はい、温度測りに行こう。
Unatan, alright, let's go measure the temperature.
温度測りに行こう。
Let's go measure the temp.
もうみんな30%だから気をつけてな。
Everyone's at 30% already, so be careful.
これが最後のチャンス。
This is the last chance.
温度計持ってる？
Do you have the thermometer?
温度計は、リビングの
The thermometer is
あのあそこに置いてある。あ、それもそうだよ。
in the living room over there. Ah, that's it too.
あ、これもやで。
Ah, this too.
ウナたん、ウナたん持ちな。
Unatan, you hold it.
せっかくやし。
Since we're here.
はい。
Yes.
頑張れ。頑張れウナたん。
Good luck. Good luck, Unatan.
はい。行きます。
Yes. I'm going.
2.5, 3.3. はい、僕も付いてるよ。
2.5, 3.3. Yes, I'm with you too.
見えないしゅばで見守っていてくれ。
Watch over me as an invisible Shuba.
てかあの扉開けられるのかしら。
I wonder if that door can be opened.
ぶっ壊れてる扉が。
The broken door...
これ入...
Let's go in...
あ、閉まった閉まった。
Ah, it closed, it closed.
なってるぞ。
It's happening.
あ、開かない。ちょっと待って、
Ah, it won't open. Wait a sec,
あ、チョコ開けるよ。
ah, Choco will open it.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
え、なんかめっちゃ鳴ってるよ！
Eh, something's beeping like crazy!
めっちゃ鳴ってるね。
It really is.
頑張れ。
Good luck.
ライト、ライト。
Light, light.
怖いよ。
I'm scared.
見えないよ。
I can't see.
ライト、ライトくれ。
Light, give me a light.
温度どう？
How's the temperature?
5.6
ウナたん、こっちは？
Unatan, what about over here?
3.0
1.5
4.2
マイナスになりません。
It's not going negative.
しゅばちゃんのさ、下のところは？
What about where Shuba-chan was, down there?
しゅばどこで死んだの？
Where did Shuba die?
このね、車のガレージ。入ってすぐ。
In the garage. Right as you enter.
死んでいる。死んでいる。
She's dead. She's dead.
今の音は何だった？
What was that sound just now?
1.8, 4.2
奥まで入ってもらっていいですか。
Could you go further in?
6.1
3.0
頑張れ。
Good luck.
4.3
マイナスになりません。
It's not going negative.
声聞こえるんだけど。
I'm hearing a voice.
やばいですけど。
This is bad.
いったん戻ろう。戻ろう。
Let's go back for now. Let's go back.
やばい、気温がやばい。すごいことになってる。
Crap, the temp is crazy. Something big is happening.
やばい、見えない。
Crap, I can't see.
足音だ！
Footsteps!
足音聞こえました！
I heard footsteps!
ぎゃあああ！
Gyaaaaa!
やめて！やめて！
Stop! Stop!
ルーナ！やめてー！
Luna! Stop it!
あーちゃん、死んじまった！
A-chan, I died!
ヤバイって！
This is bad!
ルーナ！
Luna!
死んだ。アカンって。
She died. This is bad.
やばーい！
Oh no!
（笑）うひょー。
(Laughs) Whoa.
いたいたいたいた！
There she is, there she is!
頑張れチョコ先生、仇を討て！
Go for it, Choco-sensei, avenge her!
え、ってことはなんだ？ってことはなんだ？
Eh, so what is it? What is it?
あいつ暴れやがって！
That guy's going wild!
待って待って待って！
Wait, wait, wait!
戦えるものがないんだって！
I don't have anything to fight with!
えー！これなんだ？
Eh! What is this?
あとそしたら...
Then after that...
これは？
What's this?
あと何だ？
What else?
氷点下じゃなかったから雷獣ってこと？
It wasn't freezing, so it's a Raiju?
氷点下にはならなかったね。
It didn't become freezing.
ってことは雷獣じゃないですか？
Then isn't it a Raiju?
やれ！雷獣だな！
Do it! It's a Raiju!
帰ってこれなかった...
I couldn't make it back...
ちょば！
Suba!
あ、チョコ先生が一人で...
Ah, Choco-sensei is all alone...
逃げたわ...
She escaped...
ごめんね、二人とも！
Sorry, both of you!
あいつうるせーよ！あ、でもスバルも載ってるや。
That guy is so noisy! Oh, but Subaru is listed too.
なんでやねん！
Why is that!
なんでなんで？置いてかないでー。
Why, why? Don't leave me behind!
今度は二人で帰るよー。
Next time we'll go home together.
くなよ！当たり！
Don't come! Correct!
え？雷獣？
Eh? Raiju?
だから雷獣って！
I told you it was Raiju!
何それ？
What's that?
なんか新しいの出てきてたんやけど。
Something new showed up.
なにこれ！
What is this!
アンロックしたぞ！
I unlocked it!
アンロック... 雷獣。
Unlock... Raiju.
行きた？雷獣初めてだったね！
You okay? That was our first Raiju!
難しい。
Difficult.
ムズいね、これ！
This is hard!
雷獣、何何？
Raiju, what is it?
雷獣って何？
What's a Raiju?
何だったんだ？何だったんだ？
What was it? What was it?
雷獣とは...
Raiju is...
19番や。
Number 19.
プロジェクターとオーブとレベル5。
Projector, Orb, and Level 5.
雷の化身。雷鳴ってたよね！
Incarnation of thunder. There was thunder!
確かになってたな。
It definitely was.
あ、そういうこと？
Oh, is that it?
普段は大人しいけど、力を蓄えて狂暴化...
Usually quiet but turns violent after gathering power...
なるほど！
I see!
なるほどね！
そういうことか！
So that's it!
特徴、電子機器を常に誤作動させている。え？
Characteristic: always making electronics malfunction. Eh?
ってことは...
Which means...
さっきのピーピーピーピーとかやな。
Like that beep-beep-beep earlier.
あれか！
That was it!
なるほどねー。
I see.
全然気づかなかったぜ。
I didn't notice at all.
難しい。
Difficult.
でもルーナとチョコ先なんか大丈夫そうだったね。
But Luna and Choco-sen seemed okay.
行けそうだった。
We seemed fine.
楽しかった。
It was fun.
もう一回。
One more time.
お疲れ様でした。
Thank you for your hard work.
お疲れ様でした！
Good job everyone!
あっちなのだー！あっちなのだ！
Over there! Over there!
ふうー。
Phew.
あ、ちょっと酔っちゃったのら。
Ah, I got a little motion sick.
大丈夫かい、ルーナ。
Are you okay, Luna?
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
いや、まだまだやりたいことあるのらよ。
No, there's still more I want to do.
まだまだある？
Still more?
なかなか頑張ってるのら。
You're doing your best.
本当に。
Truly.
めちゃめちゃ頑張ってた。
She was working so hard.
頑張ってたよ。
She worked hard.
いつもライブとかでもさ、一緒に歌っているけどさ。
We always sing together at lives and stuff, but...
もっとね、距離感が近いカラオケがしたいの。
I want to do karaoke where we're closer together.
距離感が近い？
Closer together?
カラオケ。
Karaoke.
距離感近い？
Closer?
このメンバーを目の前にしてカラオケ？
Karaoke with these members right in front of us?
したいの！カラオケしたい。
I want to! I want to do karaoke.
ガチ？
Seriously?
だから今日のためにね、後ろにカラオケルームも作ってもらったのら。
So for today, I even had a karaoke room made behind me.
なにー？
What?
すごい！
Amazing!
早速行くのら、みんな行くのら！
Let's go right away, everyone let's go!
行こう行こう！
Let's go, let's go!
わあ、到着なのららら！
Wow, we've arrived!
おおー、すごい！
Oh, amazing!
見て、かわいい！
Look, how cute!
かわいい！
Cute!
これルーナたんのね、カラオケルームなのらよ。
This is Luna-tan's karaoke room.
えー、これ食べれるの？お菓子、お菓子！
Eh, can we eat this? Candy, candy!
どう？どう？すごいでしょ？
How is it? Amazing, right?
すごい、なんかいるじゃん！
Amazing, someone's here!
ルーナイト持ってる！ルーナイト持ってるよ！
They're holding a Lu-knight! They're holding a Lu-knight!
見て！
Look!
おるのら。
They're here.
ほんとだ！
Truly!
持ってる。
They're holding it.
スバルがルーナイトを持ってる。
Subaru is holding a Lu-knight.
すごーい！
Incredible!
まあ、カラオケセットといえばね、タンバリンとかね。
Well, when you think of a karaoke set, there's a tambourine and stuff.
タッチパネルもあるしね、クッションもあるから。
There's also a touch panel and cushions.
なんかティータイムセットみたいのあるじゃないですか。
There's even something like a tea time set.
かわいいでしょ。
Cute, right?
え、ピアノもあるよ、ピアノも。
Eh, there's a piano too.
そう、ルーナたんのピアノ。
Yeah, Luna-tan's piano.
ま、でも今はちょっとね、ピアノ置いてあるとお部屋が狭いの。
Well, but right now, having a piano here makes the room narrow.
今日は消すのらよ。
I'm going to erase it today.
え、消すの？
Eh, erase it?
消すわ。
Erasing it.
え、ボタン一つで消えた！
Eh, it disappeared with one button!
消えろ！
Disappear!
あー！待って待って待って！
Aah! Wait, wait, wait!
そんな…え、言い方すごお前。
That's... Wow, you have a really impressive way of saying things.
びっくりしちゃった。
I was so surprised.
お歌をね、3人で歌うのらよ！
We're going to sing, the three of us!
やったー！
Yay!
みんなじゃあ早速、じゃあ好きなとこ座って。
Everyone, go ahead and sit wherever you like.
え、ここ？なんか後ろも…
Wait, here? The back too...
後ろのこれ可愛い！
The stuff in the back is so cute!
可愛いー！
So cute!
お、ね、ぼたんちゃんもいるから。
Oh, look, Botan-chan is here too.
ぼたんちゃーん！
Botan-chaaan!
ちょこちょこルーナたんここに揃ってます。
Choco-Choco and Luna-tan are all lined up here.
素晴らしい！
Wonderful!
すごいじゃん！
That's amazing!
え、ここルーナんちなの？
Wait, is this Luna's place?
そうだよ。お城の中なのら。
Yes, it's inside the castle.
おまえんちすげーな、ガチかよ。
Your place is incredible, seriously?
実はお城の中にカラオケルームあるの。
Actually, there's a karaoke room inside the castle.
わざわざ作りました、今日のために。
I had it made specifically for today.
すごい！なんか色々あるよ。
Wow! There's so much stuff.
あっちクッションもあれなのらよ。
And look at those cushions too.
え、可愛い！ぱっぱやん！ぱっぱやん！
Eh, cute! Pappa-yan! Pappa-yan!
ぱっぱクッションも作りました。
I made Pappa cushions too.
ぱっぱクッション！
Pappa cushions!
可愛いじゃん！すげー！
They're so cute! Awesome!
ま、今日は3人でね、楽しく歌うのら。
Well, today the three of us will have fun singing.
みんな乗って！乗ってね！
Everyone, get excited! Get hyped!
わかった！ノリが大切だから、カラオケだからね。
Got it! Vibes are important since it's karaoke.
マジで全然カラオケ行かんから。
I seriously never go to karaoke.
久しぶりにカラオケだー！
It's been a while since I've done karaoke!
スバルはルーナイトだけどね。わかった？
Subaru is a Lu-knight, you know. Got it?
じゃあルーナイトと一緒にね、歌いたいと思いますね。
Then I'd like to sing together with the Lu-knight.
じゃあ早速歌うか！
Now, shall we sing?
歌お！
Let's sing!
行こ！
Let's go!
最初は何を歌うの？
What are we singing first?
まずは最初、これがいいかな。ピピピピピ…
First, maybe this one... pi-pi-pi-pi-pi...
何何何、めちゃめちゃ打ってるじゃん！
What, what, what? You're typing like crazy!
はい、これ！
Okay, this one!
何？
What?
何これ？
What's this?
ライオン
Lion
まさかこの曲！？
No way, this song!?
一人で歌うの寂しいから、チョコたんと一緒に歌うのら！
I'd feel lonely singing this alone, so I'll sing it with Choco-tan!
誰に捧げるんですか？
Who are you dedicating it to?
コネクター、ぼたんちゃんに捧げます！
I dedicate it to the Komeks and Botan-chan!
星を廻して 世界の真ん中で
Spin the stars in the center of the world
くしゃみすれば どこかの森で 蝶が舞う
If I sneeze, a butterfly will dance in a forest somewhere
君が守る ドアの鍵を 預けてよ
Hand over the key to the door you're protecting
恥ずかしい物語 舐め合っても 大丈夫
Even if we lick each other's shameful stories, it's okay
生き残りたい 生き残りたい
I want to survive, I want to survive
まだ生きていたいくて
I want to stay alive still
星座の導きで いま、見つめ合った
Guided by the constellations, we gazed at each other now
ノリノリやねー、ルーナ！
You're really into it, Luna!
カラオケだもん！
Because it's karaoke!
生き残りたい 途方に暮れて
I want to survive, lost and confused
東西へ向かおう
Let's head east and west
高気圧 この星の氷河を 襲う
High pressure attacks the glaciers of this planet
捧げたい 蜜を飲んだ 唇
I want to offer my lips that drank nectar
遠き物語 混じり合う 骨の奥まで
Distant stories mingle to the core of our bones
生き残りたい 生き残りたい
I want to survive, I want to survive
まだ生きていたいくて
I want to stay alive still
星座の導きで いま、見つめ合った
Guided by the constellations, we gazed at each other now
生き残りたい 君を連れて
I want to survive, taking you with me
キラリ 枯れてゆこう
Sparkling, let's wither away
誇り高い物語 混じり合う 骨の奥まで
Proud stories mingle to the core of our bones
ぼたんちゃん生きてる！？ ライオンやで！ ライライオンやで！
Botan-chan, you alive!? It's Lion! Li-Lion!
サケー！
SAKE!
サケってボソッと言うなボソッと。
Don't just mutter 'Sake' under your breath.
お前の魂見せてくれ！
Show me your soul!
生き残りたい 埋まらない傷跡
I want to survive, with these unfillable scars
光 恐れてた
I was afraid of the light
許されたい命が今
The life that wants to be forgiven
火花を散らす
Now sends sparks flying
彷徨い果てて 君の隣で
After wandering to the end, by your side
ほてり鎮めたい
I want to soothe the burning heat
本能のままに
Following my instincts
生きてたい 眠らない
I want to live, I won't sleep
オハヨ！
Morning!
生き残りたい 崖っぷちでいい
I want to survive, even if it's on the edge
君を愛してる
I love you
目覚めたい命が今
The life that wants to wake up
惹かれ合った
Now has been drawn to you
狂気に変えて 祈り捧ぐよ
Turning it into madness, I offer my prayer
君を愛してる
I love you
星座の導きで
By the guidance of the stars
生き残りたい まだ生きてたい
I want to survive, I want to keep living
君を愛してる
I love you
本気を見せてあげるまで
Until I show you my true self
私 眠らない
I won't sleep
バカ売れしてるんだろうな、今の。
That must be a huge hit right now.
ほら見て、ハッスルしてるじゃん、チョコ先。
Look at that, Choco-sen is really hustling.
あ、ダンス、チョコ先生、ダンスがうまい。
Ah, the dance, Choco-sensei, you're good at dancing.
ボタ～ン！オイよ～。オイよ～。
Botan! Oi yo~. Oi yo~.
何でチョコ先、途中でこっち来たん？
Why did you come over here halfway through, Choco-sen?
え、ルーナと。本当だよ、何で？
Eh, with Luna. You're right, why?
何も言わず帰ってきた。一人でぼっち、やりたかった。
She came back without saying anything. I wanted to do a solo.
ルーナのターンやん。そら歌う。何で一丁前にしょうがって。
It was Luna's turn. Of course she'd sing. Why are you acting so high and mighty?
何か一人ポツンて可哀想だったから。今日主役ルーナなのに。
Because you looked so lonely all by yourself. Even though Luna is the star today.
なるほどね、こんな感じね、今日は。
I see, so that's how it's going to be today.
こんな感じ。疲れ切ってるじゃん。
Like this. You look exhausted.
どうでしたかチョコ先、1曲目終えて。
How was it, Choco-sen, finishing the first song?
いや、なんか、あんまりこうやってみんなと一緒にカラオケに行く機会がないから、ちょっとドキドキしちゃった。
Well, I don't really have many chances to go to karaoke with everyone like this, so I was a bit nervous.
でも確かにさ、チョコ先、ホロライブのカラオケ企画さ、何回かあったけど出た？
But you're right. Choco-sen, there were a few Hololive karaoke projects, did you appear in any?
出たことないの。お呼ばれされてないかも。
I've never been. Maybe I wasn't invited...
嘘でしょ、ちょっと悲しい。呼ばれてない。悲しいのら。
No way, that's a bit sad. Not invited. How sad.
なるほどね、でもスバルも出たことないからさ、ガチで？
I see. But Subaru hasn't been in them either. Seriously?
ルーナも出たことないから、今日一緒に...
Luna hasn't been either, so today together...
全員で初。カラオケだー！
It's a first for all of us. Karaoke!
4年目のルーナも生き残れるよう頑張るのら。
I'll do my best so that 4th-year Luna can survive too.
頑張れ！牡丹ちゃんも一緒に遊んでほしいのらな。遊ぼうね。
Good luck! I want Botan-chan to play with us too. Let's play together.
次の曲入れちゃおうかな。
I think I'll put on the next song.
え、次は誰が歌うの？ねえ、誰、誰歌うの？
Eh, who's singing next? Hey, who, who's singing?
何を歌うんですか、ルーナさん。次は、こちらを歌いたいと思います。
What are you going to sing, Luna-san? Next, I'd like to sing this.
何？何なの？準備してもらって。
What? What is it? Get ready.
誰と歌うんですか。スバルさん。
Who are you singing with? Subaru-san.
天城越え
Amagi-goe
え、マジで？歌う。ルーナさん、一緒に歌ってくれるんかな。
Eh, seriously? We're singing. Luna-san, will you sing it with me?
何その喋り方。選曲どうなってんの。
What's with that way of talking? What's with this song choice?
スバル、この歌歌ってみたくて。天城越え、歌わせていただきます。
Subaru wanted to try singing this song. I'll be singing Amagi-goe.
頑張って覚えました、この日のために。
I worked hard to memorize it for today.
隠しきれない 移り香が
The lingering scent that can't be hidden
いつしか あなたに 染みついた
Has before I knew it, stained you
誰かに盗られる くらいなら
If you're going to be stolen by someone else
あなたを殺して いいですか
Would it be okay if I killed you?
寝乱れて 隠れ宿
Sleep-disheveled in the hidden inn
九十九折り 浄蓮の滝
The winding path to Joren Falls
舞い上がり 揺れ堕ちる
Soaring up and swaying down
肩の向こうに あなた...
Beyond your shoulder, you...
山が燃える
The mountain burns
何があっても もういいの
Whatever happens, I don't care anymore
くらくら燃える　日をくぐり
Passing through the dizzyingly burning fire
あなたと...
With you...
あまぎー
Ama-gi...
ごーえー！
---goe!
いいわよ！いいわよ！今よ！
Nice! Nice! Now's the time!
ビブラート！
Vibrato!
手動で口の中で、ヴェヴェヴェって。
Manual vibrato inside the mouth, like "ve-ve-ve."
やるのらよ！ヴェヴェヴェ...
I'll do it! Ve-ve-ve...
チョコ先生！チョコ先生どこに...
Choco-sensei! Where is she...
私も後ろで自撮り棒カメラマンを。
I'll be the selfie stick cameraman in the back.
口は開かない
Lips remain closed
二人のカラス
Two crows
二人でいたって
Even when together
寒いけど
It's cold, but...
嘘でもいいから
Even if it's a lie
あたたかい
It feels warm
何？日？
What? Day?
さよなら？神保町？
Goodbye? Jinbocho?
神田橋！
Kandabashi!
うらんでも
No matter how much I resent
からだうらはら
My body says otherwise
あなた...
You...
山が燃える
The mountains are burning
くらくら燃える
Dizzying, burning
地をはしり
Running across the earth
あなたと越えたい
I want to cross it with you
あまぎーごーえー！
Amagi-goe!
スバ、すごいじゃん！うまい！
Suba, that was great! You're good!
ルーナ式ビブラートうまい！
Your Luna-style vibrato is good!
迷い恋
Straying love
風の群れ
Flock of wind
あまぎーついたー！
Amagi---reached it!
うらんでも
No matter how much I resent
からだうらはら
My body says otherwise
あなた...
You...
山が燃える
The mountains are burning
くらくら燃える
Dizzying, burning
地をはしり
Running across the earth
あなたと越えたい
I want to cross it with you
あまぎーごーえー！
Amagi-goe!
スバ、うまくなってね？
Suba, haven't you gotten better?
ビブラートうまくなってね？
Your vibrato has gotten really good!
ルーナ式ビブラートね、完全にコピーさせていただきました。
I've completely copied the Luna-style vibrato.
うますぎる！
You're too good!
何がよ！
What is?
ビブラートうますぎて曲止まっちゃった。
The vibrato was so good the song stopped.
嘘でしょ。
No way.
終わったって。終わった？終わったらしい。
It's over. It's finished? Seems so.
ということでね、どうでしたか？ルーナさん、スバルの天城越えは？
So, how was it? Luna-san, what did you think of Subaru's Amagi Goe?
すごいビブラートがよくなってましたね、最初に比べて。
The vibrato has improved a lot since the beginning.
ちょっとマスターするの早すぎなのらけど。
Though you mastered it a bit too quickly.
でも、最初の歌い出し、ルーナの癖強すぎてどうしようかと思った。
But at the start, Luna's quirks were so strong I didn't know what to do.
癖強くしてた。
I was making them strong.
なんかチョコ先生！あ、ごめん。
Hey, Choco-sensei! Ah, sorry.
なんか一人で自撮りしてるんですけど。
She's just taking selfies by herself.
二人のてえてえを見ながら自撮りしようかなと。
I thought I'd take some selfies while watching you two being wholesome.
てえてえじゃねえだろ別にさっきの。
That wasn't exactly "wholesome" just now.
ずっと自撮りしてましたね。
She's been taking selfies the whole time.
今日、可愛い曲多いからちょっとネタ曲入れようかなと。
There are lots of cute songs today, so I thought I'd add a joke song.
まだ始まって二曲目ですよ、ルーナさん。
It's only the second song, Luna-san.
どうしちゃったんですか。
What's gotten into you?
可愛い曲を選ぶ予定なのらよ。
I'm planning to pick cute songs.
次何？次はね...
What's next? Next is...
これを歌うかな。
I think I'll sing this.
何歌うの、何歌うの、何歌うの！
What are you singing, what are you singing!
テンション高けえ人いるなあ。
Someone's really hyper.
ちょっと走って、体温めようと思って。
I'll run a bit to warm up my body.
何歌うんですか。次は誰と歌うの？
What are you singing? Who are you singing with next?
次は、こちらを歌わせていただきます。
Next, I will perform this song.
キューティーハニー
Cutie Honey
チョコ先生、行くわよ。
Choco-sensei, here we go.
今度こそ私の曲ね。
This time it's finally my song.
行くわよ！すごいノリノリなんですけど。
Here we go! She's really into it.
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！チョコ先、決めてくれよ！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Choco-saki, show 'em what you've got!
このごろはやりの女の子
The girl who's popular these days
おしりのちいさな女の子
The girl with the small bottom
…を、ハニー フラッシュ！
...Honey Flash!
だってなんだか　だって　だってなんだもん
Because, I don't know why, because, because...
お願い　お願い
Please, please
近よらないで　あー
Don't come close, ah
私の　ハートは
My heart is...
チュクチュクしちゃうの
Pounding...
いやよ　いやよ　いやよ　見つめちゃいや
No, no, no, don't stare at me
ハニー フラッシュ！　ハニー フラッシュ！
Honey Flash! Honey Flash!
セクスィー！
Sexy!
スバスバスバスバ！
Subasubasubasuba!
チョコ先生！ チョコ先生カメラに向かってハニーフラッシュしてくれよー！
Choco-sensei! Choco-sensei, give us a Honey Flash towards the camera!
スバルカメラ待機してるよー！
Subaru-camera is waiting!
イマドキの　女の子
Today's girls
ぷっくり　ボインの　女の子
Chubby and curvaceous girls
こっちを向いてよ　ハニー
Look this way, Honey
だってなんだか　だって　だってなんだもん
Because, I don't know why, because, because...
お願い　お願い
Please, please
近よらないで
Don't come close
私の　お鼻が
My nose is...
ピクピクしちゃうの
Twitching...
いやよ　いやよ　いやよ　見つめちゃいや
No, no, no, don't stare at me
ハニー フラッシュ！
Honey Flash!
いいよ　いいよ　いいよ！ ハニーフラッシュが足りなーい！
Nice, nice, nice! Not enough Honey Flash!
どんだけかけんねん！
How much are you going to give me?!
チョコさんの歌い方強っ！
Choco-san's singing style is too strong!
なんかよくわからんくなるよな
I'm starting to get confused
そんなことないの
That's not true
ねえ「ぷっくりボインの」ってｗ
Wait, "chubby and curvaceous"? lol
セクシーアピール！
Sexy appeal!
あ、セクシーアピールだったｗ
Oh, it was sexy appeal lol
セクシーアピール！
Sexy appeal!
セクシーアピール　セクシーアピール！
Sexy appeal, sexy appeal!
あっちこっちの　早いモノ
Things fast and here and there
ふっくら　おはなの　女の子
Chubby-nosed girl
こっちを向いてよ　ハニー
Look this way, Honey
だってなんだか　だって　だってなんだもん
Because, I don't know why, because, because...
お願い　お願い
Please, please
追いかけないで
Don't chase me
私のおめめが
My eyes are...
シクシクしちゃうの
Crying...
いやよ　いやよ　いやよ　見つめちゃいや
No, no, no, don't stare at me
ハニー フラッシュ！
Honey Flash!
みんな、じゃーぼー！
Everyone, jya-bo-!
セクシーだったのらねー！
That was sexy, wasn't it?!
チョコ先生途中のこの動きすごかったｗ
Choco-sensei, that move in the middle was amazing lol
なに？
What?
これこれ！このハニーフラッシュやってて
This one! This Honey Flash move!
そんなんやってたん？
I was doing that?
こういう腰クネクネしてさ　セクシー！
This hip-swaying! It's so sexy!
すげー！
Wow!
なにその動き初めて見たｗ チョコ先生詳しいのな
What's that movement? I've never seen it before lol. You're so knowledgeable, Choco-sensei.
ななねー　セクシーといえばね
Right? When it comes to sexy...
なのら！
Nanora!
さてｗ
Well then lol
ここまで来てしまったか…
We've come this far...
ここまで…！
This far...!
あっという間なのらねー
It went by in a flash, didn't it?
なんでそんな…なんでそんな…どういう感情？ｗ 正座して座ってるみたい今の
Why are you... why are you... what kind of emotion? lol You look like you're sitting formally right now.
ルーナさっきからすごいよな…謎のSE「いや～」みたいなｗ
Luna's been amazing for a while now... That weird SE like "Iya~!" lol
ルーナさんのSEがすごいのよ 楽しくなっちゃったの
Luna-san's SE was amazing. I just got excited.
だってカラオケだもん 楽しいじゃん！
Because it's karaoke, so it's fun!
最高だね！
It's the best!
じゃあ、次はね、最後。みんなで一緒にノリノリで歌うののなよ
Well then, next is the last one. Let's all sing together energetically, nanora.
お！なんなんなん？
Oh! What is it, what is it?
なになになに？
What, what, what?
ピピピピピピ！ これ、三人で行くののなよ
Pi-pi-pi-pi-pi! We're doing this with three people, nanora.
OK!
三人でこの歌歌うののな。楽しくノリノリで！
Singing this song with these three, nanora. Energetically and fun!
おどるポンポコリン
Odoru Pompokorin
なんでもかんでも　みんな
Anything and everything, everyone
おどりを　おどっているよ
Is dancing along
いつだって　わすれない
I'll never forget
エジソンは　えらいひと
Edison was a great person
そんなの　じょうしき
That's common knowledge
タッタタラリラ
Tatta-tara-rira
ピーヒャラ　ピーヒャラ　パッパパラパ
Pii-hyara pii-hyara pappa-para-pa
ピーヒャラ　ピーヒャラ
Pii-hyara pii-hyara
おへそがチラリ
Giving a peek of the belly button
タッタタラリラ
Tatta-tara-rira
ピーヒャラ　ピーヒャラ　パッパパラパ
Pii-hyara pii-hyara pappa-para-pa
ピーヒャラ　ピーヒャラ
Pii-hyara pii-hyara
おどるポンポコリン
Odoru Pompokorin
ピーヒャラ　ピーヒャラ
Pii-hyara pii-hyara
おなかがへったよ
I'm hungry
おなかすいたー！
I'm hungry!
あの子も　この子も　みんな
That kid, this kid, everyone
いそいで　あるいているよ
Is walking in a hurry
ジンバシラのカゲカラ
From the shadow of a temple pillar
オワライゲイニントウジョウ
An entertainer appears
ッタッタタラリラ
Tattattararira
ピーヒャラ ピーヒャラ
Pi-hyara pi-hyara
パッパパラパ
Pappa parapha
ピーヒャラ ピーヒャラ
Pi-hyara pi-hyara
パッパパラパ
Pappa parapha
ピーヒャラ ピーヒャラ
Pi-hyara pi-hyara
ニンジンイラナイ
No carrots needed
ッタッタタラリラ
Tattattararira
ピーヒャラ ピーヒャラ
Pi-hyara pi-hyara
パッパパラパ
Pappa parapha
ピーヒャラ ピーヒャラ
Pi-hyara pi-hyara
オドレ ポンポコリン
Dance, Pompokorin
ピーヒャラ ピーヒャラ
Pi-hyara pi-hyara
オナカガヘッタヨ
I'm hungry
イツダッテ ワスレナイ
I'll never forget
エジソンハ エライヒト
Edison was a great man
ソンナノ ジョーシキ
That's common knowledge
ッタッタタラリラ
Tattattararira
ピーヒャラ ピーヒャラ
Pi-hyara pi-hyara
パッパパラパ
Pappa parapha
ピーヒャラ ピーヒャラ
Pi-hyara pi-hyara
オヘソガチラリ
A glimpse of the belly button
ッタッタタラリラ
Tattattararira
パッパパラパ
Pappa parapha
ピーヒャラ ピーヒャラ
Pi-hyara pi-hyara
オドレ ポンポコリン
Dance, Pompokorin
ピーヒャラ ピーヒャラ
Pi-hyara pi-hyara
オナカガヘッタヨ
I'm hungry
ピーヒャラ ピーヒャラ
Pi-hyara pi-hyara
パッパパラパ
Pappa parapha
ピーヒャラ ピーヒャラ
Pi-hyara pi-hyara
オドレ ポンポコリン
Dance, Pompokorin
ピーヒャラ ピーヒャラ
Pi-hyara pi-hyara
オナカガヘッタヨ
I'm hungry
お腹減った
お腹空いたー
I'm starving
お菓子食べたいのら
I want to eat snacks!
あー楽しかった
Ah, that was fun!
楽しかった？
Was it fun?
めっちゃ楽しかった
It was so much fun!
みんなで歌おうっつって、最初誰も歌わなくてさ
I said let's all sing together, but at first no one sang...
すげー裏切られたかと思ったよ
I thought I was really betrayed!
全然誰も歌ってなかったもんね
Yeah, no one was singing at all.
途中から出だした おたけびみたいに
You started in the middle like a war cry.
思い出したようにやりだした
You started doing it like you just remembered.
さっきまで無言やったやろーが
You were silent until just now!
急な テンション上がってきたんだね
Suddenly your tension went up, huh?
違うよ、音楽があってやっていいのかわからなかったの
No, I didn't know if I was allowed to join in with the music.
なるほどね
I see.
ここに来てね、あ、でもね、今日一緒に歌えて楽しかった、ありがちゅね
Coming here, ah, but anyway, it was fun to sing together today, thank you.
よかった
I'm glad.
楽しかった
It was fun.
これからもまた一緒に遊んでなならね
Let's play together again from now on.
ほななー！
See ya!
みんな、バイバイ！
Everyone, bye bye!
またね！
See you!
えっ、あれ？
Eh, wait?
帰れってこと？
Does that mean go home?
あ、はい。
Ah, yes.
帰ろうってこと。
It means let's go home.
スバ、また…え、また遊ぶ…
Suba, again... eh, let's play again...
スバル、行くわよ
Subaru, let's go.
あ、チョコ撮ってあげるよ
Ah, I'll take a picture for you, Choco.
え、何？二人で撮るの？
Eh, what? Are you two taking one together?
またねー！
See you!
ほんまに行っちゃったのな
They really left...
なんのなら、ちょっとみんないなくなっちまったけど
Well, everyone's gone now...
あ、でも！
Ah, but!
でもこのあとルーナからも告知があるんだったわいななー
But after this, Luna has an announcement too!
さあ、みんな、どうだったなら？
Well, everyone, how was it?
ホラゲーもカラオケも楽しかったならー
The horror game and karaoke were fun!
最近ホラゲーも耐性ついたと思うのならね、ドナタ
I think I've gained some resistance to horror games lately, everyone.
ということで、ここでグッズ紹介なのら！
So, it's time for the goods introduction!
こちらです！ドドン！
Here it is! Ta-da!
まずは1つ目、こちら！
First, this one!
ふきふきバスタオル！
Wiping Bath Towel!
こちらはね、かんざきパパ描き下ろしのふきふきバスタオルなのら
This is the Wiping Bath Towel newly drawn by Kanzaki-papa.
ルーナイトと、パンパと、しゅばぬドックと一緒にね
Together with Luna-knight, Panpa, and Shubanu-dog.
お風呂に入っている可愛いイラストなのら
It's a cute illustration of us in the bath.
ちょっとセクシーだけど、可愛くパパに描いてもらったのら
It's a bit sexy, but I had Papa draw it cute.
そして2つ目、デデン！
And second, ta-da!
高級クラブ ルーナグラス！
High-class Club Luna Glass!
ルーナたんといえばやっぱりドブロクということで
Speaking of Luna-tan, it has to be unrefined sake.
可愛い丸いフォルムを大事にしたお酒のグラスをグッズにしたのら
I made a sake glass with a cute round form into a product.
みんなこのグラスを使って、一緒にルーナたんとお酒飲むのら
Everyone use this glass and drink sake with Luna-tan.
そして3つ目は、デデン！
And the third one, ta-da!
こちら、ルーナイトスリッパ！
This is the Luna-knight Slippers!
ルーナイトスリッパ
LuKnight Slippers
ルナの...
Luna's...
スリッパ〜！
Slippers!
ルーナイトという名のね、もうスリッパの、ルナの大好きなカラーでね、こちらをね
Slippers named "LuKnight" in my absolute favorite colors, and I want...
みんなに履いてもらってフミフミフミフミしようかなと思ってグッズにしたんなら
...everyone to wear them and go pitter-patter, so I made them into merch.
ルーナイトは是非履くべし！
LuKnights should definitely wear them!
そして、全部セットには
And in the full set...
活動3周年記念フルセット
3rd Anniversary Celebration Full Set
ほかほかバスタオルのイラスト、パパの、ポストカードがついてくるのら
...comes a postcard with Papa's bath towel illustration.
フルセット購入特典 箔押し複製サイン＆メッセージ入りポストカード
Full Set Bonus: Postcard with Gold-Foil Replica Signature & Message
こちらは箔押しの複製サインになってるので
This one has a gold-foil replica signature, so...
バスタオルはお風呂場、ポストカードは机に飾って眺めてほしいのら
...I want you to use the towel in the bath and display the postcard on your desk.
そして最後はルーナイト、ルーナイトにお手紙を書いてきたのら
And lastly, I've written a letter to the LuKnights.
ちょっと取ってくるのらね
I'll go get it now.
みんなちょっと聴いてほしいのら、ルナたんのお手紙を
Everyone, please listen to Luna-tan's letter.
ルーナイトへ♡ ホロライブに入ってもう3周年になりました
To LuKnights. It's already been 3 years since I joined Hololive.
ワガママ言ったり、怒ったり、笑ったり、ルーナイト達と過ごす時間はあっという間なのらね
Being selfish, getting angry, laughing... time spent with LuKnights flies by.
毎日楽しいをありがちゅ〜♡
Thank you for making every day fun!
いつかの配信でお話ししたホロライブに骨を埋めるという気持ちは今も変わらねえのら
My wish to be buried in Hololive that I talked about before remains unchanged.
ルナはルーナイトのために頑張り続けていくから
Luna will continue to work hard for the LuKnights.
これからの活動でもっともっとしゅきを伝えさせてなのらね。ルナより
I'll express my love even more in my future activities. From Luna.
恥ずかしいな
That was embarrassing.
ということで、これからね4周年目もみんなよろしくなのら。またね〜
So, I'm looking forward to our 4th year together. See you!
出演
Cast
姫森ルーナ
Himemori Luna
癒月ちょこ
Yuzuki Choco
大空スバル
Oozora Subaru
獅白ぼたん
Shishiro Botan
撮影・企画補佐　カバー株式会社
Filming/Planning Assistance: Cover Corp
イラストレーター　天川さっこ
Illustrator: Amakawa Saeko
ロゴクリエーター　柊椋
Logo Creator: Hiragi
カラオケ部屋デザイン　月と犬
Karaoke Room Design: Tsuki to Inu
企画　姫森ルーナ
Planning: Himemori Luna
協力　ルーナイト達
Cooperation: LuKnights
姫森ルーナ 3周年記念
Himemori Luna 3rd Anniversary
おつるーなー！
Otsuruuna!
ばいばーい！
Bye-bye!